<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.5">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-04-05T13:52:16-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Etna Docs</title><subtitle>Documentation for the Mount Etna data library system</subtitle><entry><title type="html">This Week</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/etna/update/2017/11/06/this-week.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="This Week" /><published>2017-11-06T15:13:05-08:00</published><updated>2017-11-06T15:13:05-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/etna/update/2017/11/06/this-week</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/etna/update/2017/11/06/this-week.html">&lt;p&gt;We add a ‘query builder’ to our manifest editor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the key ways to grab data via Timur is through &lt;em&gt;manifests&lt;/em&gt;. A manifest
is a request for data and calculation which sews together a number of different
ways of pulling data from across Mount Etna - for example, raw data from Magma
and calculations from Pythia or Rtemis. Manifests get used all throughout Timur
to make the basic data requests required for making plots and performing other
basic functions, but users can also write their own manifests for pulling down
custom datasets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The main data source for a manifest is, of course, Magma, which is accessible via
a query API (documented &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/mountetna/magma/wiki/Query&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;).
The Magma query API is extremely expressive and can download complex subsets of
the entire data graph for a project with a single query.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, composing such a beast is not always easy. For this reason we’ve added
a query builder to ease the process. To begin, select the model you wish to
collect:
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/query1.png&quot; alt=&quot;Select a model&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then select ‘::all’ if you wish to map values from multiple records from this model (the most common type of query):
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/query2.png&quot; alt=&quot;Select ::all&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last, select a value attribute from the model that you wish to map.
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/query3.png&quot; alt=&quot;Select value&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your query will now appear and can be copy/pasted into your manifest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For good measure, you can click “+” on a model to add some filters to it:
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/query4.png&quot; alt=&quot;Add filters&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">We add a ‘query builder’ to our manifest editor.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Mount Etna Explodes!</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/etna/2017/10/26/mount-etna-explodes.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Mount Etna Explodes!" /><published>2017-10-26T16:13:05-07:00</published><updated>2017-10-26T16:13:05-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/etna/2017/10/26/mount-etna-explodes</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/etna/2017/10/26/mount-etna-explodes.html">&lt;p&gt;But don’t worry, we’re comfortable working amidst volcanic ejecta!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is our inaugural post. In this space we intend to document the travails
and successes of our effort to create a fantastic bioinformatics platform and
facilitate excellent research at UCSF (and elsewhere).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the uninitiated, Mount Etna is a series of interacting applications that
present a data system, which organizes all of the different kinds of data
associated with scientific research projects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The key players:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Magma&lt;/em&gt; - the data warehouse, magma disgorges red-hot data to all interested parties using an expressive query interface, and gobbles up new data using friendly loaders.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Timur&lt;/em&gt; - the data browser, where data may be viewed, downloaded, and analyzed. Timur collects data from various Mount Etna services, interfaces with calculation services, provides custom data views tailored to specific biological applications, and provides general query and plotting tools for exploring your dataset.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Janus&lt;/em&gt; - an authentication service that holds user and project permissions.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Polyphemus&lt;/em&gt; - a workhorse who manages dispatch of work on Magma data.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Metis&lt;/em&gt; - a file service which serves up large binary files, but also supports interesting partitions of those files (e.g. BAM slicing).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">But don’t worry, we’re comfortable working amidst volcanic ejecta!</summary></entry></feed>